hello ladies and gentlemen and welcome
大家好啊 欢迎你们
today's episode we will be covering
今天 我们将介绍
facial recognition where we were trying
面部识别  我们将会
to see people and understand who the
看人  并能判断
heck they are so we need a process we
他们是谁 我们需要一个过程
need a step-by-step way to do this and
需要一步步来做到这一点
our step by step process is on the page
我们的分步流程在页面上
before you number one are we even
第一 我们怎么知道是
looking at a face how would we know such a thing
我们看的是一张脸呢 该如何判断
enter calculus well he said nothing
我们要用到微积分
I'm scared it's fun I swear what is this
不用害怕 它很有趣 我发誓
what are we doing here so this is called
那我们究竟要做什么呢
a hog I know down on the farm here we go
这是方向梯度图
with calculus this it's actually
以及微积分
incredibly easy to calculate this
它非常容易计算
first of all what this is is a histogram of
首先  方向梯度直方图是什么
oriented gradients now what is a gradient
什么叫做梯度
a gradients super simplified is a flow
梯度是简化版的流
it's the rate of change it's a
它是一个变化的速度
flow we're just gonna say flow as it
我们还说称它为流
sounds simpler and it is the same thing
因为听起来更简单 也是一回事
so in this particular instance it's the
所以在这个情况下 它是
flow of light towards dark or of dark
光线流向黑暗 或黑暗
towards light whichever which that's
流向着光   无论哪个都很酷
cool that's just a cool thing
这就是一件很酷的事情
so all that aside I swear so easy to
所以除此之外 我发誓计算
calculate this it is literally just
都很容易 几乎全都是
subtraction amazing but even though it
减法 真酷 但是虽然
is so simple this does not mean that we
它很简单  这并不意味着我们
have to climb to the top of this mountain ourselves
必须自己爬到山的顶端
because oh oh what is this
这是什么
this right here is a giant so
这是个伟大的东西
ladies and gentleman we have found a
女士们先生们 我们找到了巨人
giant whose shoulders we will stand on
我们会站在巨人的肩膀上
that's the analogy I was going for and
这是一个类比
this Giants name is get frontal face detector
这个巨人的名字是 获取正脸探测器
amazing so what we're gonna do
所以我们要做的
is just call this giant like hey giant
只是叫这个巨人 嘿巨人
can you can you do this like crazy
你能不能为我
gradient thing for me I just don't want
做这个渐变 我不想要自己做
to bother with it was like absolutely
然后它思考了一下
consider it done and then you get this
然后你就得到这个了
guy this guy right here so why is this important
就是这个 为什么这很重要
that we have this this hog as
我们有这个方向梯度直方图
it is referred to so what we do is we
所以我们要做的
have this is kind of kind of our our model
有点像我们的模型
this is our heart if someone
这是我们的心脏 如果有人
were to ask you hey what what faces look
问你 嘿脸是什么样子的
like in the computer were to respond it
电脑就会回应它
would literally give you this top left
给你一个左上角图像
image oh yeah faces they kind of look
脸就是长这样的
like this this is what faces look like
这就是脸的样子
and with that if anyone shows them an
如果有人向他们展示了一张图片
image they're like hey is there a face
问他们这里有脸吗
in here you're like oh actually yeah it
你会回答是的有
looks kind of similar to what I know to
这看起来有点类似于我知道
be in the general realm of faces so
的一般的脸
that's that's really cool and I hope you
这真的很酷 我希望你
think that that is kind of cool and
也这么认为 这很酷
actually that crazy-complicated just
实际上它非常复杂
yeah it looks similar to this it's a face
是的它看起来很像一张脸
so number two and this is another
第二 这也很有趣
fun one you want to be able to determine
你想要确定
if this is a weird photo if this is not
这是不是一张奇怪的照片
you at your best you know it was picture
这不是你最好的状态  你知道
day and you just had a yeah yeah this is
拍照片那天
it you forgot to brush your teeth yeah
你忘了刷牙了
you know we didn't get your makeup your
或者你没有化妆
morning coffee you just look a little
你早上没喝咖啡  你看起来
weird it's okay it's fine what we can do
有点奇怪 没关系
is some basically think of Instagram to
我们可以想想Instagram
capture get your filters heard those are
它通过滤镜捕捉你的倩影
a thing and you know spruce yourself up
所以你看起来又正常了
to it to a more normal sense so there
你看起来精神又振奋了
are certain things you don't want to go
但是有些事情你又不想太过分
too far on because you know eventually
因为最终有人会问
people are like hey that's is that even
这真的是你吗
you anymore and that's another thing
这是另一回事了
that you're a computer can struggle with
计算机在这种情况下 识别你也很困难
like I really don't know if that's him
就像我真的不知道那是不是他
anymore because there's there's just so
因为可能是化妆
much makeup or whatever so we do that
或其他原因  不管怎么样
and we have a thing for that I'm actually not sure
一件事我实际上不确定
I think I left that out
我好像把它删去了
because it's like some really simple
因为它非常简单
it's the same thing Instagram uses so I
这与Instagram使用的一样
think you're familiar with this or
所以我就当你很熟悉它
something of that nature
或者是同类的东西
so we do that you look normal you look
所以我们这样做了 你看起来很正常了
good it's picture day you look good
很好 今天拍照 你看上去不错
number three we want to be able to pick
第三， 我们希望能够选择一些特征
some things out like okay so we have
比如说这张脸
this face we know it's a face but what
我们知道这是一张脸 但是
about this face what do we know about
它有什么特征呢
this face what are we looking for we're
我们在寻找什么
looking for a big nose we're looking for
我们正在寻找大鼻子
big lips we're looking for freckles we
寻找大嘴唇  雀斑
could confer in those fancy Egyptian eyes
那些埃及人奇怪的眼睛
sure I don't know things so should
我也不敢肯定
we do that and we kind of go through a
该不该这样做 我们现在
process of doing some such thing now you
正在经历这个过程
may be quiring Walker this sounds like
你可能在问了 沃克 这看起来
super fancy code yet again false we
又是超级花哨的代码 错了
found some more Giants ladies and gentlemen
我们发现了更多的巨人 女士们先生们
so we want to do is do
所以我们要做的
encoadings basically the things we know
就是编码 基本上是我们知道的
about this face so the image is this
关于这张脸的信息 所以图像是这样的
this top line here who's pointing out with my fingers
第一行 我用鼠标指出来了
which doesn't make no sense so these
这些没有任何意义
guys are the images these are what we
这是我们的图象
what we can see and then what we do is
我们能看到什么 我们要做的
we do in encoadings and we take things and
就是编码 我们收集信息
and we learn about the nose and you know
了解鼻子 或者
the ears and whatever and this is what
耳朵 和其他特征
the algorithm your your your computer
这就是你计算机的算法
their little machine learning guy he's
它们就是机器学习的内容
like hey what do i what do I even look
就像它问你  嘿我要看什么
at this is what it looks at so we do
这就是它要看的信息 所以我们这样做
this thought all this stuff and in the
所有的这些步骤与想法
end we have these two things we have
最后我们有这两件事
what we know you know somehow someway
我们通过一些途径 某时 知道了什么
it's another topic we have gone through
这是我们讲过的另一个话题
and learned the face of for instance the
我们已经学习了 比如说
one here is Joe Biden but it can be
乔拜登的脸  但它可以是
anyone there's so many just amazing
任何人 世界上有这么多棒的人
people out there let's say your mom okay
比如说 你的妈妈吧
you know the face of your mom and then
你知道你妈妈的脸 然后
you get it you get a new picture someone
你得到了一张图片
who sends you a picture in like dude I
某人给你发了一张图片
saw your mom in the supermarket and she's
说他在超市看见你妈妈了
awesome or whatever she bought you
她真棒 她给你买了
Donuts get excited you can look at that
甜甜圈 你很兴奋 你可以看看
you do all these fancy math things and
你做了所有这些酷炫的数学
then what you end up with is this this
你最终得到的就是这个
encoding this you know extracted feature layer
编码  你知道提取特征层
all these fancy words you know her
这些酷炫的词语 你知道
particular nose and a particular you
她的鼻子 或者是雀斑
know freckles and you're like oh she has
或者是 哪里有疤痕
a scar right there I know that's my mother
然后你就知道了 这是我妈妈
that's her
是她
so you compare those two and if they
所以你比较两个图像
match mama dearest how arc that doing my
如果匹配的话 有多匹配
mom's awesome so plug for Deborah's type
我妈妈的美貌颜值
out there and if they don't match
如果不匹配
like dude that's just to look like she's
她们只是看起来很像
not as awesome but I'm sure she's
但她没有你妈妈这么棒 但我确定
awesome
她也很棒
so yeah that's gonna short ish gist of
所以 这就是有关面部识别
facial recognition and all its glory so
以及相关内容的简介啦
thank you I hope you learn something and
谢谢你 我希望你学到了什么
have a good day
祝你今天愉快